Mr. Rong,
容公子
you'd better not interfere with this case.
这事我劝你还是少管为妙
The arrest last night was usual.
昨晚的抓捕行动非同一般
Those who were arrested
而且被抓去的人
can hardly be released.
也都很难被放出来
I understand.
我明白
I won't put you through this.
我自然不会让刘处长为难
Now that he can't be released,
既然现在放不出来
could you do me another favor?
那就有劳你费心一下
At least let us know where he's locked
好歹让我们知道关在哪里
so that we can have him taken care of.
这样我们也方便去打点嘛
Fine, then.
行吧
I'll ask about it for you.
我替你问一下
What's your friend's name?
你朋友叫什么名字
Feng.
姓冯
Feng Shixun.
叫冯世勋
Shi for world
世界的世
and Xun for merit.
功勋的勋
By the way,
对了
he's a doctor at Red House Hospital.
他是红房子医院的医生
As far as I know,
据我所知
those who were arrested last night
昨晚被抓捕的
turned out to be revolutionaries.
可都是一些革命党啊
Revolutionaries?
革命党
There must be something wrong.
搞错了吧
He would never be a revolutionary.
他绝对不可能去参加什么革命党
He's a rigorous and self-disciplined man
他平日里是一个严谨 自律
who works very hard.
勤奋工作的人
You must have got him wrong.
绝对是搞错了
He has parents and a sister.
他上有老 下有小
Why would he be a revolutionary?
怎么可能加入什么革命党呢
Mr. Rong,
容公子
it's hard to tell.
这事可不好说呀
I asked about him for you.
我也替你问过了
Those who were arrested last night
昨晚抓捕的
turned out to be famous cadres.
都是一些榜上有名的干部
Considering your friend was arrested last night,
你这朋友既然是昨晚被抓的
he couldn't be a common doctor.
那身份肯定不简单哪
At present,
而且现下
they're all locked in Tilanqiao Prison.
他们被统一关在提篮桥监狱
I couldn't interfere with that place.
我的手也伸不过去啊
I know it's difficult.
我知道这件事情难办
But please take the trouble
那就有劳您多费费心
to find some helpers for me.
帮忙找找关系
Fine.
好吧
All right.
好
Thank you.
有劳了
Mr. Jiashang,
大少爷
I heard you say
我刚才好像听到你说
that Dr. Feng was arrested.
冯医生被抓了
What happened?
是怎么回事
You heard it right.
你没听错
Dr. Feng is in trouble.
冯医生出事了
He was arrested as a revolutionary.
他被当成革命党抓走了
Considering what you just said,
听你刚才说的
We can't save him
难道就算我们出手
even with the power of the Rong family?
都还不能把人救出来吗
The situation isn't clear yet.
现在情况还不明确
But it's indeed tricky.
不过的确有些棘手
No way.
不可能的
How's that possible?
怎么可能
Lady, there you are.
小姐 你在这呢
What's up?
怎么了
Master woke up.
老爷醒了
Ms. Chen went out early this morning to get some medicine for him.
陈妈一大早就出门给老爷抓药去了
Ma'am asked you to serve Master with breakfast.
太太让您过去伺候老爷用早餐呢
You know his temper.
你知道老爷这脾气
If he waits for a long time...
这等久了
I'm on it.
我这就过去
If you don't want to serve me,
你要是不想伺候我啊
you can leave.
可以走啊
Look at you.
你说
Are you pulling a long face
你摆出这一副寡妇脸
to disgust me?
故意给我看啊
I'm not dead yet.
我这儿还没死呢
What?
怎么
You want to mourn for me already?
就想给我守孝了
No.
没有的事
I just...
我只是
I just heard about something.
刚听说外边出了点事
Have you heard about it, Master?
老爷听说了吗
Last night,
昨天夜里
the police arrested revolutionaries everywhere,
警察满大街的抓革命党
saying they would execute reactionaries.
说是要处置反动派
Why is a woman like you
你一个女人
so interested in politics?
对政治这么感兴趣吗
What?
怎么
Your friend was arrested?
有你认识的人被抓了
No.
没
Miss Feng's brother was arrested.
是冯先生的哥哥
Dr. Feng, I mean.
就是冯医生
He was arrested.
他被抓了
Why does his arrest
冯医生被抓了
make you worried?
你愁什么呀
I'm not worried.
没有
I'm just curious.
我就是好奇
I heard Mr. Jiashang make several calls.
我刚才听大少爷打了好几个电话
Is it
这件事
very dangerous?
很凶险吗
It depends.
事在人为
It depends on how it'll be handled.
就看怎么运筹帷幄了
Particularly, this is an unusual case.
尤其是这种案子不比寻常
Whether there's evidence,
有没有证据
whether he's guilty,
有没有罪
and what crime he has done
有多大罪
will simply be decided by the judge.
全在审案子的人的一句话
With powerful helpers,
关系到了
it can be solved easily.
怎么都好办
But without them,
关系要是没到
even money won't help.
使多少钱都没用
What?
怎么
Will my ungrateful son
是嘉上那个吃里扒外的东西
use our own money
要拿我们容家的钱
to save
去 去救那个
that sinister woman's brother?
丧门星的哥哥吗
Are you saying
这么说
that he can be saved?
还是能救出来的
Looks like you care a lot
看来你对这个姓冯的
about Dr. Feng.
还真是挺关心的
Dr. Feng
冯医生
saved my son Jiakang and me.
是救了我和康儿母子一命的恩人
Though Jiakang was too unlucky
虽然康儿福薄
to survive,
没能熬过来
he managed to live for a few months
但也多亏了他
with Dr. Feng's help.
才在这世上活了几个月
I'm grateful to Dr. Feng.
我对冯医生感恩戴德
I certainly care about his life.
自然关心他的安危
Jiakang?
康儿
Like I said,
我刚才说了
it is possible
这种事啊
to save him.
不是没有可能
With powerful helpers, there won't be any problem.
关系到了怎么都好办
However,
只是
Jiashang is
嘉上那个小子
too inexperienced.
资历太浅
He can't use such helpers.
动不了那些关系罢了
Master,
那老爷
will you help Mr. Jiashang?
就不能帮帮大少爷
He hasn't begged me.
他也没来求我呀
That...
那个
That woman...
那个姓冯的
Feng Shizhen
姓冯的那个女人
utterly discredited my family.
害得我们容家身败名裂
Why would I help
我为什么要反过来
her brother?
帮他哥哥呀
If she kneels
她要是
and begs me,
跪在地上求我
I'll think about it.
我还是可以考虑考虑的
Open the gate.
开门
Thank you.
谢谢
No problem.
好
You got the chance for her.
明明是你打点来的机会
Why didn't you tell her?
你为什么不直接告诉她
I don't want her to have any psychological burdens.
我不想她有任何的心理负担
My family owes it to her.
这是我们家欠她的
What's your name?
叫什么名字
Feng Shizhen.
冯世真
Fine.
好
This way.
这边
Her brother's case is tough.
她哥哥这事还挺难办的
Even Chief Liu fails to help.
连刘处长都无能为力
Jiashang,
嘉上
do you know Li Dezheng?
你知不知道李德正
He's the director of Shanghai Police Headquarters.
他是现在上海警察总局局长
It was his men
这次的抓捕行动
who arrested those people.
就是他底下人干的
Before he took office,
他在上任之前
he was on good terms with your father.
和你爹的交情不错
How about begging your father?
你要不要去求求你爹
My father?
我爹
He wants Shizhen's family to suffer.
他巴不得世真一家都不好过呢
He won't help.
怎么可能伸出援手
What do we do, then?
那怎么办呀
I can't think of a solution.
我也没招了
Every man has his weakness.
是人就会有弱点的
We can hit on what he likes.
总能投其所好
Are you saying...?
你是想
Right.
没错
Let's go.
我们走
Open the gate.
开门
Go.
走
Feng Shixun!
冯世勋
You've got a visitor!
有人来看你了
Thank you, sir.
谢谢大哥
Fine. I'll go have a cigarette.
行 我去抽根烟
Be quick.
快点啊
All right.
好
Shixun,
哥
did they beat you?
他们打你了
If I weren't beaten,
不挂点彩
how could I prove
哪敢说自己
I was once in prison?
在牢里走过一遭呢
I'm lucky enough.
我情况算很好了
You managed to come in
你还能进来
and bring me a suit.
还能给我送些衣服
Shizhen,
世真
how's everything going out there?
外面情况现在怎么样了
Everything is in a mess.
外面现在乱得很
Insurgents are being hunted throughout the city.
满城都在追捕进步人士
Everyone is disquieted.
闹得风风雨雨的
What about Father and Mother?
那爹妈呢
Are they all right?
他们还好吗
Yes.
好
I've kept it from them.
瞒着他们呢
I told them
就跟他们说
you were taken here for investigation
你是请过来接受调查
and you could go home after it.
等调查完就可以回家了
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's my fault that...
都是因为我才
We're a family.
一家人
Don't say that.
你别说这种话
Shixun,
哥
I don't understand politics.
我是不懂什么政党纠纷
But I know
但我知道
this is your political ideal.
这是你的政治理想
You haven't done anything wrong.
你没有做错什么
For my problem,
为了我的事
you must have suffered these days.
这些天辛苦你了
I had thought
我本以为
I could get you out earlier.
还能早几天把你救出去
But the situation is tense.
但是现在外头风头紧得很
I'm afraid you'll have to wait for days.
恐怕还要再过些日子
Yesterday, some comrades were taken out
昨天有几个同志被带出去
and didn't come back.
就再也没回来
I'm afraid they were killed secretly.
恐怕已经被秘密杀害了
Shizhen,
世真
if anything happens to me,
如果哥出什么意外的话
tell Father and Mother
跟爹妈说
- that I... - Shixun,
儿子
you won't.
不会的
You won't die.
一定不会的
You're the backbone of our family.
你可是咱家的顶梁柱
You won't be dead.
一定不会有事的
Don't overthink.
别多想了
I'll find a solution as soon as I can.
我会抓紧想办法的
Fine.
好
All right. It's about time.
行了 时间差不多了
You should leave.
该走了
Go back home.
回去吧
Do protect yourself.
一定要保护好自己
Wait for me.
等我
Shizhen,
世真
when I'm away,
我不在
take good care of Father and Mother.
照顾好爹妈啊
Don't let anyone else get hurt again.
咱家不能有人再出事了
Rest assured, Shixun.
放心吧 哥
Come on. Get in.
来 上来吧
You saw him?
见到人了
Why didn't you
这个事
ask me for help?
你为什么不来找我呀
This is my family business.
这是家里的私事
I shouldn't bother you.
不应该劳烦您的
Don't treat me as a stranger.
你跟我还这么见外
Speaking of that,
说起来
you once reminded me.
其实七爷提醒过我
I was just too careless.
是我自己大意了
Your brother is an adult.
你哥哥是成年人
He should take responsibility for his actions.
该对自己行为负责
And you know him very well.
而且他的性格你最了解
I'm afraid you couldn't persuade him.
怕是不会听人劝
Don't worry.
你放心
Their target is Zhang Guoquan,
他们的目标
instead of your brother.
不是你哥哥
Besides, your brother isn't deeply involved.
况且你哥哥涉足未深
He won't be killed for the moment.
暂时没有性命之忧
Let's spend more bribe money
再多打点些钱
and he won't suffer much
就不会让他
during the interrogation.
在审讯上受太多苦
Mr. Meng,
七爷
I want to borrow some money from you.
我想跟您借点钱
I'll pay the normal interest.
利息您跟我正常算
Is it necessary between us?
你我之间需要算那么清楚吗
We should clear up the accounts.
账还是要算清楚的
After Shixun is released,
等我大哥出来以后
I'll pay you back with the interest.
我连本带利还给您
Shizhen,
世真
I didn't mean to tell you this.
本来我不想告诉你的
But whatever...
但无所谓了
Today, you managed to see your brother
今天你能见到你大哥
because
是因为
someone helped behind you.
有人在背后打点
It was
这个人
Rong Jiashang.
是容嘉上
Will you be softhearted?
会心软吗
Your concern is misplaced, Mr. Meng.
七爷多虑了
His help is one thing.
他帮我是一回事
The blood feud between Qin Shuigen and me
我跟秦水根的血海深仇
can be another.
是另外一回事
They're irrelevant.
不相干的
As for the money,
钱的事
get it from Meng Hai.
你找孟海拿吧
I'll tell him about it.
我会交代他的
Thank you, Mr. Meng.
多谢七爷
Look at Ms. Chen.
这个陈妈
She gets such high pay,
拿着这么多的工钱
but she runs out almost every day,
三天两头地往外跑
saying she's sent by Master.
说是给老爷办事
Who knows if it's true?
也不知道是不是真的
Where's today's newspaper?
今天的报纸呢
Master will read it after breakfast.
老爷用完餐要看的
Don't worry. I remember that.
你放心 都记着呢
Lady,
小姐
the breakfast is ready.
早餐备好了
Ungrateful son!
你这个吃里扒外的东西
How dare you use our own money
竟然用我们容家的钱去救那个
to save that woman's brother?
那个女人的哥哥
They should have died in prison.
当年他们真应该都死在牢里面
I should have killed them personally!
我应该亲自动手 斩草除根
Father,
爹
such money
这些钱
doesn't belong to our family!
本来就不属于我们家
What?
怎么
You'll bribe Director Li with the money?
你要用这些钱去找李局长吗
You know what?
我告诉你
He won't help you.
人家是不会帮你的
You think after you grabbed power,
你以为篡了我的位
you could manage everything?
就会把龙椅坐稳吗
You're making our family decline.
你现在把家败成这样
He won't do you the favor!
人家是不会卖你这个人情的
Go tell Feng Shizhen
你告诉冯世真
to pick up her brother's body!
去给他哥收尸吧
Go pick up his body!
去收尸
You heard us?
你都听到了
Master, if you don't help,
是不是 老爷如果不肯帮忙的话
will Dr. Feng be executed?
冯医生就会被处决
You heard us, didn't you?
你不是都听到了吗
That's why Jiashang is
所以嘉上那个混帐东西
so exasperated.
才如此气急败坏
Master,
老爷
couldn't you do him the favor?
您就不能行行好吗
For the sake
您就看在
that Dr. Feng saved Jiakang and me,
他救过我和康儿母子一命的份上
you would do a good deed for Jiakang
你救他就是给康儿积福啊
so that he may live happily in his next life.
让他来世能投个好胎
Besides,
况且
Mr. Jiashang is your own son.
大少爷是您的亲儿子呀
He's so young and childish
他年轻不懂事
that he quarrels with you for a woman.
为了个女人和您闹
As his father,
您作为长辈
if you let go of it and help him,
如果不计前嫌帮了他
he'll regret
他只会忏悔
and feel guilty.
会愧疚
Then you can
您就可以
ask him to let you leave the room.
让他把您从房间里放出来
You can even get back to the company.
甚至还可以回公司
You don't want Feng Shizhen to be your daughter-in-law.
您不喜欢冯世真做您的儿媳
I'll think of a way
大不了我想个办法
to send her away.
把她给打发了就是
Women know how to deal with other women.
女人对付女人最有一套了
You'll deal with Feng Shizhen for me?
你要帮我对付冯世真
However,
不过
if Jiashang knows that,
嘉上将来知道了
he'll fall out with you.
会跟你翻脸的
I'm a concubine.
我一个做妾的
Whether I'm on good terms with Mr. Jiashang
和大少爷关系是好是坏
doesn't matter.
又有什么关系呢
I'm your concubine, anyway.
横竖我是跟着您的
At the worst, I'll leave the family.
大不了我走就是了
To save Feng Shixun,
为了救冯世勋
you will sacrifice so much?
你竟然愿意如此委曲求全
Fine.
好
I'll help you.
我成全你
So,
这么说
you agreed to help?
您是答应了
I'll go get Mr. Jiashang to you.
我去叫大少爷
I can save Feng Shixun simply by making a call.
救冯世勋我一个电话的事
But,
只是
you should do
先把答应我的
what you promised me.
办了吧
We need a careful plan
对付她
to deal with Feng Shizhen.
还要从长计议
It can't be done in a day or two.
这也不是一两天的事情
So...
所以
I can't wait for your plan.
我等不了你从长计议了
This isn't hard.
这事其实不难
Go to the West Hall.
你去西堂
In the third cell of the innermost bookcase
书房最里面那个书柜
of my study,
第三格
there's a gun.
里面有把枪
What do you want me to do?
您是什么意思
Don't you understand?
没听懂吗
Kill Feng Shizhen with the gun.
拿枪杀了冯世真
As soon as I'm informed of her death,
我只要听到她的死讯
I'll save Feng Shixun.
马上去救冯世勋
You want me
您让我
to kill Miss Feng?
去杀了冯小姐
Why?
为什么
Because she wants to ruin my family.
因为她要毁了我们容家呀
If she reveals what I did,
她要是把所有的事情都说出去
our family will be utterly discredited.
我们容家必定身败名裂
After you kill her,
杀了她
you can stop Jiashang from doing stupid things.
就可以阻止嘉上犯傻
you can defend our family
就可以保全容家
and do good deeds for Jiakang.
还可以为康儿积福
Isn't that good?
不好吗
We don't need to kill her, anyway.
那也不用去杀人呀
Let me talk with her
你让我去跟她好好谈谈
and make her cave in.
让她来给您服个软
Talk with her?
谈谈
If talking could solve the problem,
如果谈要是能够解决问题
I wouldn't have asked you to kill her.
还用的着闹到今天这个地步吗
Jiashang just told me
嘉上刚才可是跟我说了
that Feng Shixun would be executed
冯世勋今日正午
this noon.
将被处决
You have less than four hours.
离现在应该不到两个时辰了
Hurry up.
你得抓紧了
Otherwise, today will be the day
要不然明年今天
he dies.
你就得给他烧纸了
This noon?
今天正午
Either Feng Shixun or Feng Shizhen can live.
冯家兄妹只能保全一个
Rong Jiashang picked Feng Shizhen.
现在嘉上选了冯世真
What about you?
你呢
Who will you pick?
你选谁啊
Master,
老爷
I beg you.
我求求你
I haven't even killed a fish since I was born.
我长这么大我连条鱼都没杀过
How could I kill a woman?
我怎么可能去杀人呢
It's a quarter past eight.
八点一刻了
Feng Shixun has little time
冯世勋在这个世界上的时间
to live in this world.
应该不多了
What?
怎么样
Do you still need to think about it?
你还要再考虑考虑
How about this?
要不这样
Let me promise you something more.
我再给你个好处
After you kill Feng Shizhen,
杀了冯世真
I'll divorce you.
我就和你离婚
What did you say?
你说什么
Don't think I don't know what you want.
你别以为我不知道你的心思
You wanted to leave the family long ago
你早就想离开容家
and go far away with your beloved man, right?
跟着你的心上人远走高飞了不是吗
Kill Feng Shizhen
把冯世真杀了
and I'll let you go.
我就放过你
You can go to Feng Shixun for shelter
你就可以带着你的私房钱
with your private savings
去投奔冯世勋
and spend the rest of your life
你就可以用你一生的时间
comforting him,
去好好安慰他
asking him to forgive you,
求他原谅
and making atonement.
向他赎罪
What do you say?
好吗
I'm sorry, Mr. Rong.
不好意思啊容先生
Director Li is receiving a guest.
局长正在会客
Please wait for a bit longer.
还请你
Secretary Zhang,
张秘书
I've got an emergency.
我这件事情十万火急
Could you please
你看能不能进去
ask Director Li for an exception
给局长通融一下
so that he'll meet me first?
让我先见见局长
But...
这
Please.
拜托你了
For my father's sake.
至少看在家父的面子上
Wait a minute, then. I'll go ask him.
那你稍等
All right.
好
How did it go?
怎么样
I'm sorry, Mr. Rong.
不好意思容先生
This afternoon,
下午局长
Director Li is too busy to meet you.
没有时间了
Please come some other day.
你改日再来吧
It's all right.
没事
I'll be seated there.
那我先坐一会儿
I'll wait for five minutes.
我等他五分钟
Fine. As you wish.
好 你自便
I'm sorry, Uncle Li.
不好意思啊李伯伯
I came to bother you
这么小的事情
with such a little problem.
还要跑过来麻烦您
It doesn't matter, Xu'an.
世侄客气了
Your father and I
我和你父亲
lived in the same dorm
可是同挤着一间宿舍
when we went to school.
念书的同窗啊
We've been friends for decades.
几十年的老交情了
It's just a little favor.
帮你这点小忙
Don't bother to thank me.
不足挂齿
Unfortunately, your father died early
只是令尊英年早逝
and was buried in the US.
远葬在美国
I didn't see him before he died.
竟然没能再见最后一面
Now that you're back,
如今你既然回国了
why not come often
不妨经常过来
and visit me?
来看看我老人家
I certainly will.
那是自然的
Mr. Rong Jiashang
容大少爷
will visit you often, too.
也会常来看您的
Director Li.
李局长
Mr. Rong, you haven't left yet?
容公子 你还没走啊
Mr. Rong, I guess you also came
想必容少爷也是因为
for Dr. Feng, right?
冯医生的事情
Don't worry.
你放心
Uncle Li is very fair.
李伯伯很公正的
I've explained to him
我把前因后果
what happened.
跟李伯伯说清楚了
He knows very well
他很清楚
that Dr. Feng was involved.
冯医生是被牵扯进来的
So,
所以
the amnesty has been signed.
这个特赦令已经签完了
Thank you, Director Li.
多谢李局长
Mother,
妈
have some hot tea
喝点热茶
to warm yourself up.
暖暖身子
It's all right.
没事
I'll go check it out.
我去看看
Concubine Sun,
孙姨太
what brings you here?
您怎么来了
Is there anything wrong with Fanglin or Fanghua?
是芳林她们出什么事了吗
Has your brother
你哥哥
been released?
放回来了吗
Not yet.
还没有
Come on in.
快进来吧
Come in before we talk.
进来再说
Concubine Sun,
孙姨太
take your seat.
里面坐
Mother,
妈
this is Concubine Sun of the Rong family.
这是容家的孙姨太
Let me get you some water.
我给你倒点水
Do you know your brother
你知不知道你哥哥
will be executed this noon?
今天中午要被处决了
What?
什么
What did you say?
你说什么
Who told you that?
你从哪听来的
Why would my son be executed?
我们家世勋怎么会被处决呢
Mother, take it easy.
妈
It's not true, is it?
这不是真的对吗
I heard Mr. Jiashang talk to Master about it.
我听见少爷跟老爷在说这件事
Now that I'm aware of this,
我都听到了
how could you not know?
你怎么可能不知道
So, it's not true.
所以这不是真的
Right?
对吗
Concubine Sun,
孙姨太
who told you this?
你这消息是从哪儿来的
It's not true, of course.
这当然不是真的
Mother,
妈
I'll go check it out.
我这就去找人问问
Go check it out.
快找找
Hurry.
你快
Go check...
你去找
Concubine Sun,
孙姨太
what are you doing?
你这是做什么
Is there some misunderstanding?
是不是有什么误会
Put the gun down first.
你先把枪放下来
Let's keep cool.
有什么话咱们好好说
Master said,
老爷说了
as long as I kill you,
只要我杀了你
he'll save Dr. Feng.
他就去救冯医生
Why?
为什么呀
- Why? - Mother.
这是为什么呀
I'm sorry.
对不起
No one can save him, but Master.
只有老爷才能救他
I like you.
我也很喜欢你
I don't want to hurt you.
不想伤害你
But I don't have another choice.
可是我没有办法
Master won't save Shixun unless I kill you.
只有杀了你他才能去救他
He's dying!
他要死了
Calm down.
你冷静一点
This can't be true.
这肯定不是真的
If it were true,
如果是真的的话
Mr. Meng would tell me.
七爷不会瞒着我
Don't let Rong Dingkun fool you.
你千万不要被容定坤骗了
He's very dishonest
他这个人满口谎话
and he always lies.
信口雌黄
He can't be trusted.
他的话是不可信的
No.
不
Mr. Jiashang said that, too.
大少爷都说了
I heard him say that.
我亲耳听见大少爷说了
I don't dare to gamble.
我不敢赌
Miss Feng, if you were me,
冯小姐
would you dare to gamble
大少爷出了事
when Mr. Jiashang was dying?
你敢赌吗
Concubine Sun,
孙姨太
calm down.
你先冷静一下
Listen to me.
你听我说
Rong Dingkun hates me a lot.
容定坤他这么恨我
What if he doesn't keep his promise
如果我死了
after you kill me?
他依旧不肯兑现承诺呢
Put the gun down.
你把枪放下
I'm taking you to see my brother,
我现在就带你去见我哥
all right?
好不好
No, no, it's too late.
不不 来不及了
He'll be executed in two hours.
他还有一个时辰
Shizhen, Shizhen.
真儿 真儿
Don't move!
你别动
Mother.
妈
Calm down.
你冷静一点
As long as I kill you...
只要杀了你
After I kill you,
杀了你
Rong Dingkun will save Shixun.
容定坤就会去救世勋
He promised me.
他答应我的
As long as I kill you,
只有杀了你
he'll save Shixun.
他就会去救他
Concubine Sun.
孙姨太
Shizhen, are you all right?
世真你没事吧
Shixun.
世勋
Mother.
妈
You're back?
你回来了
I'm back.
我回来了
You'll be all right.
你不会有事的
There's no bullet in the gun.
里面没有子弹
scaring her
想吓唬一下她
so that she would beg Rong Dingkun.
让她去求容定坤
I didn't mean to hurt her.
没想伤害她
I know.
我知道
Rong Dingkun misled you to trust him.
你只是错信了容定坤那老狐狸的话
I don't blame you.
我不怪你
I'm glad...
你
you're alive.
没事就好
I'll always remember
你的这份情谊
how you tried to help me.
我会记得一辈子
My name is Sun Shaolan.
我叫孙少澜
Shaolan means great momentum.
波澜壮阔的澜
Shizhen, the letter.
世真 信
It's the letter your sister Shaoqing wrote to you.
这是你妹妹少清寄给你的信
Letter...
信
Sun Shaolan.
孙少澜
Shaolan means great momentum.
波澜壮阔的澜
I've kept it in mind.
我记住了
I underestimated my father.
是我低估了我爹
I never expected him to have an evil plan
没想到都到了这个地步
even under such circumstances.
他还能折腾出这些事来
I've bribed the police.
巡捕房那边我已经打点过了
Anyway,
不管怎么说
she's your father's concubine.
她也是你的庶母
As for the rest of the case,
接下来的事情
we'll leave it to you.
就交给你自己处理了
Where's my brother?
我哥呢
He's still in there.
他还在里面
He just came out of the prison
他刚从监狱出来
and then saw Concubine Sun die.
又遇到这样的生死之事
Emotionally,
情绪上
he's breaking down.
难免有些崩溃
Leave him alone.
让他自己待会儿吧
Today,
今天
I should say sorry.
我应该说抱歉
I shouldn't have shot her hurriedly.
我不应该那么着急开枪的
It's not your fault.
这不能怪你
You were trying to save me.
你也是为了救人
Looks like Qin Shuigen
看来秦水根
really wants to kill me.
是真的要置我于死地
Last time, he asked Hashimoto Shiori to kidnap me.
上次联手桥本诗织来绑我
Luckily, Wen saved me then.
当时幸好有阿文在
Today, he incited Concubine Sun to kill me.
今天又挑唆孙姨太来杀我
Sooner or later,
看来我和你爹
he and I will have a life-and-death struggle.
早晚会走到你死我活的那一天
I know.
我知道
What?
怎么
Your beloved woman finally died?
你心爱的女人终于死了
Concubine Sun died.
孙姨娘死了
Are you satisfied now?
你满意了吧
What a woman!
那个贱人
Quite useless.
终究是没用
Concubine Sun had a son for you
孙姨娘为你生儿育女
and she'd been your concubine for years.
跟了你这么多年
But in the end,
到头来
she was a mere chess piece, right?
她也不过是颗棋子对吧
She was with me,
人在我这儿
but she loved
心
someone else.
早不知道飞哪儿去了
Just like you,
和你一样
she was an ungrateful woman.
都是吃里扒外的白眼狼
You love Feng Shizhen
一个为了冯家的女人
and she loved Feng Shixun.
一个为了冯家的男人
Funny.
可笑
How funny!
可笑啊
Mr. Jiashang,
少爷
here are all the stock right documents
这是容家所有的股权文件
and real estate assignments of the Rong family.
和地产转让书
Mr. Jiashang,
少爷
are you really
您真的打算
(Transferred by: Rong Jiashang) transferring all these to Miss Feng?
把这些全都转给冯小姐吗
They should have been hers.
这本该属于她
After Fanghua's wedding,
等到芳桦婚礼过后
give them to her
你替我
on my behalf.
把这些都交给她
You've had hard days lately.
这些日子辛苦你了
After doing the last thing,
等忙完这最后一件事情
go back home without concern
你就安心回家
and accompany your child for his treatment.
陪孩子治病吧
Thank you, Mr. Jiashang.
谢谢大少爷
Take care.
多保重
Father,
爹
I've given you too many chances.
我已经给过你太多次机会了
I can no longer indulge you.
如今我不能再纵容你
After everything is over,
等这一切结束后
I'll atone for your sins with you.
我会和你一起赎罪
What a nice day!
天气真好
So it is.
是啊